# **MARCIA ADLER**

New York, New York

Phone: (808)551-5101 | Email: marciaadler718@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/marciaadler/ | GitHub: https://github.com/MarciaAdler |

Portfolio: https://marciaadler.github.io/MarciaAdlerPortfolio/

#### SUMMARY

I am a Product Manager with experience working successfully in teams on large projects to build products and applications to help clients achieve their business goals. I have completed requirements gathering, as well as debugging and testing products to ensure they meet the needs of clients and work as designed. I like to solve problems and find better ways to do things, by using data to drive the process. My experience in consulting and skills from my Full Stack Web Development Certificate set me up well to work with teams to not only plan and develop but also build new products and applications.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, MySQL, Express, React,

MongoDB

**Applications:** Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Asana, MySQL Workbench, GitHub **Other Skills:** Relationship building, Problem Solving, Data Analytics, Strategic Planning,

Financial Modeling/Budget Management, Business Strategy

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## Global Project Director Omnicom

2017 – 2018

New York, NY

Led international finance transformation projects to implement the company wide initiative to move to a shared service center and outsourcing model. Key Accomplishments:

- Led the requirements gathering and documentation of current state processes, which were used to develop future state processes using the new organizational structure.
- Developed the people strategy for the transformations, to ensure strategies and processes put in place would be successful and work for the employees in the organization.

## Senior Consultant - People Advisory Services Ernst & Young

2013 - 2017

New York, NY

Led teams and managed projects to help clients understand their current state and create a strategy to reach their desired goals.

Key Accomplishments:

- Led the design, requirements gathering, testing, training, and implementation for new tools and technologies that were designed and implemented, based on client requirements, to assist them in their efforts to reach a desired future state for five different M&A clients.
- Coordinated meetings and activities between different client work streams/functions and collaborated with cross-functional teams to execute deliverables on-time and help clients reach desired goals for large-scale M&A projects.
- Project managed large-scale projects including managing timelines, relationships, risks and open items, providing regular updates to leadership, and engaging sponsors to ensure teams were staying on track and aligning with the overall strategy.

- Part of a core team that conceptualized, designed, and worked with the tech team to build a tool that helped clients gather decisions on their organizational design, and allow them to upload their decisions and view on-demand data analysis on the decisions that were entered and the future state design of their organization.
- Used data to drive decision making on multiple projects, providing clients with summary and detailed data, and providing clients with guidance in making informed decisions to reach their desired goals and successfully complete projects.

## **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

MBA Finance Intern2012United TechnologiesFarmington, CTMBA Finance Intern2012Otis ElevatorFarmington, CT

## **PROJECTS**

TheViralEffect|https://github.com/MarciaAdler/Project3-

Viral2.0|https://dashboard.heroku.com/apps/hidden-everglades-28296

- App that tracks the progression of the Coronavirus and the impact on the markets and different industries
- Responsible for coding the back-end functionality and front-end design of the app. Also
  for managing team's activities and ensuring everyone was staying on track and
  troubleshooting as necessary.
- React, Bootstrap for React, JavaScript, APIs

hungrymuch?|https://github.com/MarciaAdler/ProjectOne|https://marciaadler.github.io/ProjectOne/

- App that uses an API to bring in nutritional information for food items and recipes based on a main ingredient search. Allows users to save recipes for future reference.
- Responsible for coding the search for recipes by main ingredient, including the call to the third-party API and all dynamically created items. Also worked on UI.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Materialize, APIs

## **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: Columbia University New York, NY March 2020 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

**University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT: 2013** 

Master of Business Administration – Finance/Human Capital

University of Connecticut, West Hartford, CT: 2010

Bachelor of Science – Business Administration (Business & Technology/Marketing). Summa Cum Laude.

**Certifications:** Society for Human Resource Management Certified Professional (SHRM-CP)